Hi I'm Lauren, I'm going to be discussing how to add natural highlights at home.
If you do not feel as though you would like to go to a salon, and just want to add your or change your color up a little bit, to add a little bit more dimension you can go to any drugstore or any beauty destination and get a hair home lightening kit.
Ultimately you will mix up whatever the hair lightener is that they give you.
And it will come with a little bit of a brush such as this or it may have a little bit more harder bristle then this one actually does.
You will then simply mix up everything that they give you, and follow the directions that they give you.
And you would paint it on your hair.
The best way to do that is to dip your brush in and then literally stroke it on to tiny sections that you would like to be lighter.
Lay them gently over the rest of the hair and then let them go. You would do this with each section.
You do not want to push them down because what will happen is that it will start to lighten those hairs underneath and it will cause you to have spots.
Very gently and lay them down.
So that maybe they are not even directly touching that hair that's underneath.
It will prevent any spotting and any errors that could occur.
So you are going to put it down, very gently ,just kind of release it.
You can do that all throughout the head so that way you can lighten as many sections as you want.
The one nice thing is that this is a little bit more paste so you can kind of say I like a highlight here and then you can actually put that highlight there.
If you do have a lighter hair color, more of like your very light brown, or your dark blonde the home hair kit hair lightening systems may work out a little bit better for you.
If your hair is very dark you may just want to go to your local salon because there width actions tends to not be as strong as what a professional can get and what will happen is it will leave your highlights looking very brassy, very like very orangey and very, very bright.
I tend to find that people with a lighter base color have a bit of an easier time and better results in doing home hair lighting kits.
And that is how to lighten your hair at home.